Johnny Otis Collection, 1949-2012 SC 106
Archives of African American Music and Culture
- 4. Radio Airchecks, Johnny Otis Show
  - 4.2. KPFK (Los Angeles) and KPFA (Berkeley), 1982-1994
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Harmonica and Zydeco blues, 1986?; 2 Audiotape Reels 10 in.
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of Jimmie Lunceford, Billie Holiday, Temptations, Martha & The Vandellas, Little Walter, Pete Lewis, Sam Cooke, Little Richard, Marvin & Johnny, Junior Wells, Johnny Wells & Big Walter Hornton, Aretha Franklin, Dominoes, Hank Williams, Jazz Gillum, Big Joe Turner, Helen Humes, Count Basie, Mahalia Jackson, Louis Jordan, and Clifton Chenier. Otis and friends take phone calls, talk about the Landmark Church's food drive for the homeless.
    - The Johnny Otis Show, 1986?; 1 Audiotape Reel 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Barbara Morrison
      EC10 2673
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/p38w32xz8z
      Otis plays the music of Al Green, Drifters, Dells, Charles Brown, Smokey Robinson & Miracles, Sam & Dave, Little Esther, Bobby Bland, Son House, Dominos, Percy Mayfield, Four Tops, Duke Ellington & Ivy Anderson, Sam Cooke, Clovers, Buster Brown, and B.B. King. Otis and friends promo the Landmark Church's food drive for the homeless.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Great Male Vocalists of African-American Music, 1987-01; 1 Audiotape Reel 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Nicky Otis
      EC10 2676
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/x91366d152
      Otis plays the music of Sam & Dave, Peppermint Harris, Fats Waller, Nat Cole, Al Hibbler, Ink Spots, Earl "Fatha" Hines, Jimmy Reed, Ray Charles, Gene Chandler, Little Jimmy Scott, Amos Milburn, Little Willie John, Ruth Brown, Dominos, Chords, Drifters, Jimmy Jones, and Brook Benton. Otis talks about Black music and promotes the Watts Towers Festival.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Jay McShann Night, 1987-01-06?; 2 Audiotape Reels 10 in.
      EC10 2677; EC10 2678
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/h04d67258d
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of Fats Domino, Marvin Gaye, Lightnin' Hopkins, Otis Redding, Stevie Wonder, Aretha Franklin, Ray Charles, Jay McShann, The Rays, Lee Dorsey, Moonglows, Andy Kirk, Chuck Berry, Louis Jordan, Silhouettes, Swan Silvertones, Billie Holiday, Buster Brown, Little Richard, Jimmy Reed, Duke Ellington, and Bobby Marchand. Otis takes phone calls and promotes the Landmark Church's food drive for the homeless.
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of Jay McShann, Clovers, Coasters, Ray Charles & Lily Fort, Chuck Willis, James Brown, Clyde McPhatter, LaVern Baker, Joe Turner, Count Basie, Johnny Otis featuring Shuggie Otis, Fiestas, Aretha Franklin, Drifters, Don Gardner & Dee Dee Ford, Nellie Letcher, Falcons, Little Willie John, Jerry Butler, and Sam Cooke. Otis takes phone calls, has trivia contest, and promotes food drive.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: KPFK Fundraiser, 1987-01-12; 1 Audiotape Reel 10 in.
      EC10 2376
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/s95643h933
      Otis plays the music of Big Joe Turner, Five Royales, Fats Domino, Temptations, LaVern Baker, Prince Dixon, Count Basie, Little Richard, Little Esther, Chuck Willis, Elmore James, Coasters, Bobby Bland, John Lee Hooker, B.B. King, Sam & Dave, Jimmy Reed, and Louis Jordan.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr.'s Birthday, 1987-01-19; 2 Audiotape Reels 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Barbara Morrison
      EC10 2377; EC10 2378
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/979v04841b
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of Junior Walker, Martha & The Vandellas, Ella Johnson, Count Basie, Dinah Washington, Little Walter, Bobby Bland, Little Richard, Dorothy Love Coates & The Gospel Harmonettes, Ketty Lester, Smokey Robinson, Big Jay McNeely & Little Sonny, Otis & Carla, Toussaint McCall, Benny Goodman Sextet, Ray Charles, T-Bone Walker, and Nat King Cole. Otis discusses state of affairs for Black people in America, Los Angeles' treatment of the homeless, and then takes phone calls.
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of Sam Cooke & The Soul Stirrers, Staple Singers, Barbara Morrison, Little Willie John, Elmore James, Bobby Day & The Hollywood Flames, Bobby Lewis, Sonny Parker, B.B. King, Chuck Willis, Fats Domino, Bubba Johnson, Jimmie Lunceford, Dominoes, Joe Simon, Lily of the Valley, and Ray Charles. Otis takes phone calls and promotes his food drive for the homeless.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Artists with "King" in their name, 1987-01-26; 3 Audiotape Reels 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Bernie Pearl, Bill Gardener, Ron Stevens
      EC10 2379; EC10 2380; EC10 2381
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/979v04846w
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of Bo Diddley, King Curtis, Marvelettes, Ben E. King, Little Junior Parker, B.B. King, Champs, Dells, Rays, and Earl King. Otis promotes Pearl's upcoming Louisiana-style festival.
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of The Jacks, Pilgrim Travelers, Shuggie Otis, Billie Holiday, King Pleasure, Little Esther Phillips, Albert King, Joe Tex, Koko Taylor, and Billy Stewart. Otis introduces Bill Gardner. Otis and Stevens promote their food drive for the homeless and experiences helping those on the street.
      Tape 3: Otis plays the music of Earl King, Mary Clayton, Clarence Fountain & The Blind Boys, Freddy King, Swan Silvertones, B.B. King, and Martha & The Vandellas. Otis and Pearl talk about Pearl's radio show and gospel music, then take phone calls.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Lloyd Price Tribute, 1987-01-30; 1 Audiotape Reel 10 in.
      EC10 2382
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/f46217wz8q
      Otis plays the music of Hank Ballard & The Midnighters, Lloyd Price, Smokey Robinson & The Miracles, Tampa Red, Chuck Berry, Memphis Slim, Stevie Wonder, Etta James, Ivory Joe Hunter, Jay McShann, Eddie "Cleanhead" Vinson, Mary Wells, Dinah Washington, Louis Jordan, Ray Charles, Staple Singers, and Bobby "Blue" Bland. Otis promotes his show at the Fairmont Hotel.
    - The Johnny Otis Show, 1987-02-02; 3 Audiotape Reels 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Ed Soesman, Jimmy Keyes
      EC10 2383; EC10 2384; EC10 2385
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/z80594148d
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of The Chords, Oscar Tony Jr., Ike & Tina Turner, Four Tops, Four Clefs, Ray Charles, Jimmie Lunceford, B.B. King, Clara Ward, Supremes, Aretha Franklin, Jack McVay, Mercy Dee, and Wilson Pickett. Otis and friends discuss rare records, Otis interviews Jimmy Keyes (The Chords) via telephone, Otis and Soesman take calls.
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of Wilson Pickett, Sam & Dave, Del Vikings, Channels, Clara Ward, Dinah Washington, Solomon Burke, Frankie Lymon & The Teenagers, Doves, Count Basie, Don & Dewey, Little Walter, Fats Waller, Lightnin' Hopkins, Snooks Eaglin, and Jimmy Reed. Otis and Ron Rothstein promote their food drive to feed the homeless.
      Tape 3: Otis plays the music of Jimmy Reed, Muddy Waters, Joe Turner & Pete Johnson, Ray Charles, Brook Benton, Chuck Berry, Buster Brown, Richard Berry, Clara Ward, Duke Ellington, Martha & The Vandellas, Dakota Staton, and J. Otis.
    - The Johnny Otis Show, 1987-02-09; 2 Audiotape Reels 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Dewey Terry, Johnny Harris, Nicky Otis
      EC10 2386; EC10 2387
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/910j82rf5t
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of Junior Walker & The All-Stars, LaVern Baker, Joe Turner, Coasters, Ivory Joe Hunter, Tommy Tucker, Blind Lemon Jefferson, Arthur Conley, Little Esther Phillips, Big Maybelle, Z.Z. Hill, Supremes, Staple Singers, Ann Young, B.B. King, Albert Ammons, and Louis Jordan. Otis and friends talk about the new Three Tons of Joy, take phone calls, and discuss Blue Note Records.
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of Dinah Washington, Sticks McGee, Four Tops, Stevie Wonder, Don & Dewey, Staple Singers, Supremes, Count Basie, Jesse Belvin, Billie Holiday, and Aretha Franklin. Otis plays pre-recorded conversation with Soupy Sales. Live performances by J. Otis, Terry, Harris, and Nicky. Otis and Terry talk about the new Don & Dewey record. Otis promotes food drive for the homeless.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Performers with the Names of U.S. Presidents, 1987-02-16?; 2 Audiotape Reels 10 in.
      EC10 2691; EC10 2692
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/267683365z
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of Wilson Pickett, Stevie Wonder, Jimmie Liggins, Frankie Ford, Dinah Washington, Roosevelt Sykes, Bo Carter, Slim Harpo, Temptations, Aretha Franklin, Johnny Taylor, Pete Johnson & Joe Turner, B.B. King, Drifters, Billy Eckstine, Mary Wells, Peppermint Harris, Big Mama Thornton, Wilbert Harrison, and Clarence Carter. Otis and friends chat and take phone calls. Otis promotes upcoming KPFK All Nations Gospel Festival on Friday, March 20 [1987?].
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of Mahalia Jackson, Faye Adams, Jackie Wilson, Koko Taylor, Duke Ellington, Ella Fitzgerald, Bobby Bland, Brook Benton, Muddy Waters, Fats Domino, Bull Moose Jackson, Sam & Dave, Lightnin' Hopkins, Billie Holiday, Al Green, Count Basie, Marv Johnson, Lonnie Johnson, Plas Johnson, Pete Johnson, Ella Johnson, Robert Johnson, and Abby Lincoln. Otis and friends talk about Asian influences in Western music, then take phone calls.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Tribute to Piano Players, 1987-02-23; 3 Audiotape Reels 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Harmonica Fats, Bernie Pearl, Guitar Shorty, Nicky Otis
      EC10 2388; EC10 2389; EC10 2390
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/g05f36bc5j
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of Fats Domino, Sam Cooke, Wilson Pickett, Cleo Brown, Little Richard, Huey Smith & The Clowns, Floyd Dixon, Professor Longhair, and Piano Red. Otis talks with Pearl, tells a story about Little Richard, and they discuss upcoming radio specials and concerts before taking phone calls. Otis tells the story of how he signed Iron Butterfly and Canned Heat and then lost them.
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of The Coasters, Ray Charles, Little Eva, Spiders, Jimmy Reed, Percy Mayfield, Aretha Franklin, Marvin Gaye, and Louis Jordan. Otis and guests take phone calls. Live performances by Bernie Pearl and Harmonica Fats. Live performance by Otis, Pearl, Fats, Shorty, and Nicky Otis. Pearl tells a story about Big George Smith and Phillip Walker and Otis promotes his Red Beans and Rice Festival.
      Tape 3: Otis plays the music of Harmonica Fats, Guitar Shorty, Champion Jack Dupree, Art Tatum & Joe Turner, Count Basie, Nellie Lutcher, Joe Liggins, and Otis Spann. Otis and guests discuss the origin of "The Dirty Dozens" and perform the song live.
    - The Johnny Otis Show, 1987-03-02; 3 Audiotape Reels 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Ted Hayes, Blind Joe Hill, Jimmy Tolbert, Nicky Otis
      EC10 2391; EC10 2392; EC10 2393
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/089227sz89
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of Camille Howard, Arthur Conley, Dinah Washington, Supremes, Bobby Bland, Bo Diddley, B.B. King, Harmonizing Four, Jesse Hill, Professor Longhair, Little Milton, Erma Thomas, Roy Brown, Lee Dorsey, and Chuck Berry. Otis and Hayes talk his organization to help the homeless, the "Outcry for Justice" protest and other projects.
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of Shirley & Lee, Billie Holiday, Count Basie, Ray Charles, Young Jesse, Louis Jordan, Dinah Washington, Lowell Fulson, Big Joe Turner, Teen Queens, Prince Dixon, Fats Domino, Ink Spots, Albert Collins, Lightnin' Hopkins, and Martha & The Vandellas. Otis and guests take phone calls, talk about the death of Freddy Green, the work of Lester Young, and Albert Collins.
      Tape 3: Otis plays the music of Martha & The Vandellas, Lloyd Price, and Johnny Otis. Live performances by J. Otis, Hill, and Nicky Otis. Hill talks about where he was raised, his early musical influences and experiences, how he got started in music, and being arrested for auto theft when he was young.
    - The Johnny Otis Show, 1987-03-09; 3 Audiotape Reels 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Prince Dixon
      EC10 2394; EC10 2395; EC10 2396
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/2579801862
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of Chuck Berry, Red Prysock, Dinah Washington, Otis Redding, Lightnin' Hopkins & Barbara Dane, Louis Jordan, Prince Dixon & The Jackson Southernaires, Billie Holiday, Martha & The Vandellas, B.B. King, Wilson Pickett, Lowell Fulson and Jay McShann. Otis and Dixon talk about Dixon's upcoming Gospel Caravan and other upcoming gospel concerts. Otis takes phone calls.
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of The Marvelettes, Bobby "Blue" Bland, Count Basie, Marvin Gaye, Harmonizing Four, Aretha Franklin, Big Three, John Lee Hooker, Percy Mayfield, Ray Charles, Ernie K-Doe, Johnny Otis & Eddie Vinson, Little Richard, Fats Domino, Big Joe Turner, and Johnny Otis with Little Esther. Otis takes phone calls, promotes Prince Dixon's gospel festival, and his food drive for the homeless.
      Tape 3: Otis plays the music of Brook Benton, Pine Top Smith, Billie Holiday, and Jimmy Reed. Otis takes phone calls and talks about the upcoming Red Beans and Rice Festival.
    - The Johnny Otis Show, 1987-03-16; 3 Audiotape Reels 10 in.
      EC10 3665; EC10 3666; EC10 3667
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/494v53rk6z
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of Chuck Berry, Lee Dorsey, LaVern Baker, Fiestas, Joe Tex, Charles Brown, Billy Eckstine, James Brown, Ray Charles, and Handicappers Band. Otis and friends talk about Pha Terrell and various programs on KPFK, promote upcoming gigs and take phone calls.
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of The El Dorados, Slim Gaillard, Swan Silvertones, Nat King Cole, Louis Jordan, Louis Armstrong & Velma Middleton, Johnny Otis, Wilson Pickett, Coasters, Drifters, T-Lou & His L.A. Zydeco Band, Fontella Bass, Brook Benton and Dinah Washington, Otis Redding, Bessie Smith, and Duke Ellington. Otis takes phone calls, talks about his new album and promotes an upcoming gig. Otis and Rothstein promote the Landmark Church's food drive for L.A.'s homeless.
      Tape 3: Otis plays the music of Duke Ellington, Muddy Waters, Jackie Wilson, Billie Holiday, Johnny Otis, Aretha Franklin, B.B. King, and Count Basie. Otis promotes his new album, his art show, and upcoming gigs.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Billie Holiday Tribute, 1987-03-23; 3 Audiotape Reels 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Micky Kaplan, John Patton, Barbara Sherrill
      EC10 2397; EC10 2398; EC10 2399
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/t24w52qf16
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of The Cadillacs, Sam & Dave, Fats Domino, Gladys Knight & The Pips, Silhouettes, Buddy Guy, Coasters, Billie Holiday, Bernie Pearl, B.B. King, Count Basie, Duke Ellington, and Sam Cooke.
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of Billie Holiday, Sam Cooke, Little Richard, Otis Redding, Aretha Franklin, Sonny Boy Williamson, Jimmy Reed, Five Blind Boys, Amos Milburn, Wilson Pickett, International Sweethearts of Rhythm, J. Otis, Tommy Ridgley, and Maurice Williams & The Zodiacs. Otis and Kaplan talk about Otis' upcoming art show in Kaplan's gallery. Otis and Patton talk about Jimmy Reed and African American artistic expression. Sherrill talks about the radio show she and Patton host on KPFK. Otis talks about the International Sweethearts of Rhythm.
      Tape 3: Otis plays the music of Billie Holiday, Ray Charles, Dinah Washington, John Lee Hooker, Slim Harpo, Marvin Gaye, and the Four Tops. Otis takes phone calls.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Chicago Blues Night, 1987-03-30; 3 Audiotape Reels 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Ted Taylor
      EC10 2645; EC10 2646; EC10 2647
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/q87b790s41
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of Stevie Wonder, Katie Webster, Louis Jordan, Jimmy Reed, Smokey Robinson, Jack McVay, Jazz Gillum, Koko Taylor, Count Basie, B.B. King, Lionel Hampton, Son House, Staple Singers, and Etta James, followed by a comedy segment.
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of Sonny Boy Williams, Ray Charles, Aretha Franklin, Johnny Otis featuring Big Joe Turner, Muddy Waters, Hank Williams, Howlin' Wolf, Bobby Bland, and Dinah Washington. Comedy segment followed by Otis taking phone calls and greeting Taylor.
      Tape 3: Otis plays the music of Thiam Sy Griots of Senegal, Sonny Boy Williams II, Little Walter, Bo Diddley, and Bessie Smith. Otis and Taylor talk about their livestock and the Red Beans and Rice Festival.
    - The Johnny Otis Show, 1987-04-06; 3 Audiotape Reels 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Jimmy Tolbert, Richard Berry, Cameron Turner
      EC10 2401; EC10 2402; EC10 2403
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/p98851c30s
      Tape 1 (EC10 2402): Otis plays the music of Sam & Dave, Chords, LaVern Baker, Cleftones, Big Mama Thornton, Muddy Waters, Lightnin' Hopkins, Marvin Gaye, Ben E. King, Barbara George, and Cadets. Otis talks about his art show and takes phone calls.
      Tape 2 (EC 2403): Otis plays the music of Gene Chandler, Ray Charles, Staple Singers, Dinah Washington, Johnny Otis, Louis Jordan, Jackie Wilson, Etta James, and Chuck Willis. Otis introduces Turner who talks about Radioscope and the "Jackie Wilson Marker Fund" that's being sponsored by Jack Gibson. Otis talks about the staying power of the blues and other classic forms of African American music, then greets Tolbert.
      Tape 3 (EC 2401): Otis plays the music of Count Basie & Lester Young, Richard Berry, B.B. King, Howlin' Wolf, Billie Holiday, Staple Singers, Otis Redding and Carla Thomas. Otis introduces Berry, talks to Jimmy Tolbert talk about his uncle, Lester Young, and Berry talks about current projects. Otis and guests talk about big band R&B's current popularity and which Billie Holiday songs Lester Young played on. Otis promotes his food drive for the homeless and announces upcoming concerts.
    - The Johnny Otis Show, 1987-04-13; 3 Audiotape Reels 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Richard Berry, Nicky Otis
      EC10 2404; EC10 2405; EC10 2406
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/772039rf2t
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of Ray Charles, Lionel Hampton, Joe Jones, Joe Turner, Amos Milburn, Supremes, Four Tops, Fats Domino, Howlin' Wolf, Louis Jordan, and Peppermint Harris.Otis and friends take phone calls, talk about upcoming concerts and the Red Beans and Rice Festival.
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of Etta James, Ted Taylor, B.B. King, Clovers, Marvin Gaye, Robins, Little Richard, Mitty Collier, Huey "Piano" Smith, Bessie Smith, Drifters, Charles Brown, Chords, Billie Holiday, Richard Berry, and Johnny Otis. Otis and friends take phone calls and talk about food drive for the homeless. Berry talks about reissuing some of his records.
      Tape 3: Otis plays the music of Richard Berry, J. Otis, Temptations, Jimmy Reed, Duke Ellington, Toussaint McCall, Staple Singers, Aretha Franklin, and Muddy Waters. Live performance by J. Otis, Berry, and Nicky Otis. Otis and Berry talk more about reissuing records.
    - The Johnny Otis Show, 1987-04-20; 3 Audiotape Reels 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Ken McKnight
      EC10 2407; EC10 2408; EC10 2409
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/m01b596t0w
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of Junior Walker, Big Joe Turner, LaVern Baker, Fats Domino, Four Tops, Aretha Franklin, Slim Gaillard, Lil Green, Ella Fitzgerald, and Louis Jordan.
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of Howlin' Wolf, B.B. King, Clovers, Sam Cooke, Bessie Smith, Ray Charles, Duke Ellington, Muddy Waters, Swan Silvertones, Billie Holiday, Big Mama Thornton, Wilson Pickett, Johnny Otis, LaVern Baker, Solomon Burke, and Coasters. Otis talks about food drives and the Red Beans and Rice Festival.
      Tape 3: Otis plays the music of Professor Longhair, Robert Parker, Drifters, Gladys Knight & The Pips, Fats Waller, Jimmie Lunceford, Sam & Dave, Otis Redding, Chuck Berry, LaVern Baker, Fiestas, and the Dubs. Otis and friends talk about New Orleans followed by comedy segment.
    - The Johnny Otis Show, 1987-04-20?; 1 Audiotape Reel 10 in.
      EC10 2400
      Otis plays the music of Junior Walker & The All Stars, Louis Jordan, Roy Milton, Richard Berry, Lightnin' Hopkins, Marvin Gaye, Johnny Ace, Christine Cottrell, Impressions, Swan Silvertones, Erskine Hawkins, Little Willie John, Aretha Franklin, Al Green, Barbara Morrison, Platters, Chuck Berry, Fats Domino, Ray Charles, Jimmie Lunceford, Temptations, Lloyd Price, Jimmy Reed, Count Basie, Joe Turner & Art Tatum, and Eddie "Cleanhead" Vinson. Otis takes phone calls.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Duo Special, 1987-04-27; 3 Audiotape Reels 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Roy Gaines, Bernie Pearl, Nicky Otis
      EC10 2410; EC10 2411; EC10 2412
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/g54x51pq7t
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of Wilson Pickett, King Curtis, Albert King, Temptations, Lee Dorsey, Sonny Terry & Brownie McGhee, Ike & Tina Turner, Aretha Franklin, Nat King Cole, Roy Gaines, Bo Diddley, Bobby Day, and Bessie Smith. Otis talks about the theme of the night with Pearl. Gaines discusses his first musical experiences and influences, making music for "The Color Purple" soundtrack with Quincy Jones, and Hank Williams.
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of Delmar & Margie Evans, Brook Benton & Dinah Washington, Roy Gaines, Ted Taylor, Don Covay, and Lionel Hampton. Live performance by Gaines, Pearl, and Nicky Otis. Otis takes phone calls and promotes his food drive for the homeless.
      Tape 3: Otis plays the music of Esther Phillips & Mel Walker, Shirley & Lee, Duke Ellington, Count Basie, B.B. King, Ruby McCoy, Richard Berry, Etta James, Staple Singers, Billie Holiday, Louis Jordan, Johnny Otis, Sam & Dave, James & Bobby Purify, Otis Redding, and Ray Charles.
    - The Johnny Otis Show, 1987-05-04; 3 Audiotape Reels 10 in.
      EC10 2413; EC10 2414; EC10 2415
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/504r56t052
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of Etta James, B.B. King, Jackie Wilson, Veretta Dillard, Dinah Washington, Ted Taylor, Richard Berry, Joe Louis Walker, Joe Williams, Marvin Gaye, Aretha Franklin, Frankie Ford, Snooks Eaglin, Little Esther Phillips, Ruby McCoy, Lionel Hampton, and Slam Stewart & Major Holly. Otis talks about his Red Beans and Rice Festival, upcoming blues concert, and opening of a new nightclub.
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of Lionel Hampton, Slam Stewart & Major Holly, Little Junior Parker, Bobby "Blue" Bland, Johnny Otis & Don "Sugarcane" Harris, Joe Tex, and Count Basie. Otis takes phone calls on the subject of giving proper credit to Black artists who created blues, R&B, jazz and other music genres. Otis and friends promote their food drive for the homeless.
      Tape 3: Otis plays the music of Count Basie, Bessie Smith, Staple Singers, Fats Domino, Ray Charles, Oscar Brown Jr., Four Tops, Moonglows, Billie Holiday, Drifters, Jimmy Reed, Muddy Waters, Clarence "Frogman" Henry, and Irma Thomas.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Big Joe Turner Tribute, 1987-05-18; 2 Audiotape Reels 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Norman Harris
      EC10 2416; EC10 2417
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/z70890z535
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of Cadillacs, Chuck Berry, Marvin & Johnny, Little Eva, Impressions, Big Joe Turner, Gladys Knight & The Pips, Wilson Pickett, Lowell Fulson, Etta James, Staple Singers, Mississippi John Hurt, B.B. King, Richard Berry, Bobby Day, Ted Taylor, Louis Jordan, Big Joe Turner & Elmore James, Ray Charles, Martha & The Vandellas, Eddie Floyd, Fats Domino, Aretha Franklin, Jimmy Reed, Irma Thomas, and Drifters. Otis and friends, including Norman Harris of Norm's Rare Guitars, talk about the local Cajun festival and a film about Ernie Andrews followed by a comedy segment. Otis and friends talk about the Red Beans and Rice Festival, ask for volunteers, and Otis takes phone calls.